Saleem Adebayo

14, Infinity Estate Lekki-Ajah, Lagos, Nigeria +2348080034289, bayoleems@gmail.com

PROFILE

Highly skilled professional AI/ML Developer and Engineer and Data Analyst, with a strong background in machine learning/data science, data analysis and data annotation. Experienced in developing AI applications and solutions, collaborating with crossfunctional teams, and developing machine learning models. Other valuable skills include Python Automation and Web Scrapping.

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a role as AI/ML Engineer to leverage my expertise in developing AI solutions that drive business growth and optimize operational efficiency.

EDUCATION

LADOKE AKINTOLA UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY, OGBOMOSHO

Oyo, Nigeria

Bachelor of Technology, Civil Engineering

October 2017 – May 2023

Emphasis: IT and Programming

EXPERIENCE

AB-InBev AI Developer

Lagos, Nigeria July 2022 – till date

- Developing ML models and annotation processes to ensure high-quality labeled datasets for training models.
- Restructuring codebase for faster code execution and debugging.
- Annotating and labeling datasets.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to understand project requirements and deliver accurate and timely annotations.
- Training and evaluating machine learning models.
- Working closely with AI engineers to implement and deploy machine learning models into production.
- Participating in regular team meetings and brainstorming sessions to improve AI solutions.
- Keeping up with latest developments in the AI community globally for idea creation.

POC-Eve

Data Annotator

Lagos, Nigeria July 2022 – May 2023

Labeled large image dataset.

- Validated dataset for optimal AI model training process.
- Outlined data labeling documentation and guidelines.

Computer Vision [FREELANCE]

Computer Vision Engineer

Lagos, Nigeria November 2022 – till date

- Writing python code for object detection and inference for videos and images
- Building and training models with custom datasets
- Fine tuning models for better inference for detection
- Implementation of tracking algorithms for regional counting and global detection evaluation
- Generating detection and tracking data from model output

Data Science [FREELANCE]

Lagos, Nigeria October 2021 – till date

Data Scientist

- Training and building ML model for prediction.
- Performing EDA on datasets
- Building recommender systems with prediction models
- Creating data visualization with python data science libraries
- Feature engineering and hyper-parameter fine tuning for model optimization

Data Analysis [FREELANCE]

Lagos, Nigeria October 2021 – till date

Data Analyst

- Writing SQL statements for better data extraction and storage optimization
- Web scraping data from approved websites for data analysis
- Working closely with Backend Engineers on codebase structures
- Creating data visualization dashboard with Power BI
- Data cleaning and EDA on datasets with python libraries

SKILLS

- High proficiency in Python programming language.
- Professional data science, data analysis and web scraping skills
- Basic knowledge of Git essentials and repository management
- Advance knowledge of machine learning algorithms and deep learning frameworks. (PyTorch, and TensorFlow)
- Advance knowledge of image processing, segmentation and classification
- Proficient API creation and execution skills with FastAPI, Flask and Django
- Intermediate user interface skills with Streamlit app and Flask (rendering HTML templates)
- Familiarity with Command Line activities
- Good database management knowledge and practices
- Advance knowledge on Natural Language Processing, Retrieval Augmented Generation
- Familiarity with Large Language Models and GenAI Models like GPT4, Llama, RoBerta and many others.
- Familiarity with cloud platforms (e.g., Azure, AWS, Google Cloud) and their AI services
- Strong computer vision techniques
- Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills
- Strong communication and collaboration abilities

PROJECTS

AI Music Playlist Maker

Role: AI Developer

With GPT, Spotify and Flask for prompting, authentication and UI respectively, to make a web application that generates an excellent music playlist on Spotify with a given prompt and number of songs.

Conversational AI Form

Role: AI Developer

Accessing OpenAI API to create a chatbot that filters user input for form filling and returning a conversational respond for empty or not filled out parts of the forms.

Computer Vision Analysis

Role: Computer Engineer and AI Developer

With OpenCV and custom YOLOv8 model for object detection on image and video, utilizing the Streamlit framework to present inferences, tracking and counting analysis. Also, providing an interface for filtering and customization of detections.

Auto-Annotation

Role: AI Developer/Engineer

Using pretrained AI model and SAM model to label datasets and draw polygons or bounding boxes on SKUs.

Document Data Entry Automation

Role: AI Developer

Creating an automated process for filling template documents with data inputs from JSON or dictionary data structures.

Loan Approval Prediction

Role: Data Scientist and Data Analyst

Using ML libraries, scikit learn and pandas to perform data analysis on loan application dataset and model training to visualize and predict loan approvals.

Netflix Data Analysis

Role: Data Analyst

Performed extensive data analysis and data visualization on Kaggle Netflix open source dataset.

Object Detection and Regional Tracking and Counting

Role: Computer Vision Engineer

Using YOLOv8 to detect objects and tracking algorithms like SORT and Euclidean tracker to track and assign unique IDs to detected objects.

Object Counting and Computation

Role: Computer Vision Engineer

Using OpenCV and Openpyxl to detect and count objects passing through a particular Region of Interest (ROI) and storing the data output to an excel spreadsheet.

Similarity Image Detection

Role: Computer Vision Engineer

Using ML libraries such as scikit learn and OpenCV to get similarity levels in images by using different metrics such as MSE, SSIM, MSSIM and ORB to get similarity index.

Computer Vision Research

Role: Data Annotator

Giving comprehensive methodology of the annotation process involved in the computer vision workflow in relation to image detection and recognition.

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. Certificate of completion for Deep learning: Model Optimization and Tuning
- 2. Certificate of completion for Artificial intelligence Foundations: Machine Learning
- 3. Certificate of completion for Learning SQL Programming
- 4. Certificate of completion for Learning Python
- 5. Certificate of completion for Git Essential Training
- 6. Certificate of completion for MLOps Essentials: Model Development and Integration
- 7. Certificate of completion for PyTorch Essential Training: Deep Learning
- 8. Certificate of completion for Django Essential Training
- 9. Certificate of completion for Deploying Django Apps

References are available upon request.